Canadian Association of Geographers: Western Division fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Canadian Association of Geographers: Western Division fonds
1958 - 2011
F-144
Q106659775
50 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Canadian Association of Geographers: Western Division
The British Columbia Division of the Canadian Association of Geographers came into being in 1958. In 1968 this Division became the Western Division of the Canadian Association of Geographers (WDCAG) and they included members of the parent body from Alberta and the Western States. The purposes of the organization are the promotion of geographical study, teaching and research. The Division holds annual meetings and publishes a newsletter and occasional papers.
published
Full
Revised
Title is based on the provenance of the fonds.
The fonds consists of records made or received by the WDCAG and reflect the administration and operation of the organization. Includes correspondence, minutes, reports, newsletters and publications, and other documents.
Original order was maintained by the Archivist where possible. Where no order was apparent, the materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Organizations; Land, settlement and immigration
The collection was donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by the WDCAG.
In 2006 the Archives received an accrual of newsletters from 2005 and conference material from 2005 and 2006. This accrual was processed in 2007. Further accruals are expected from time to time.
Please consult the inventory for the Department of Geography fonds, F-12.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. A more complete administrative history of the early years of the WDCAG is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Organizational records, 1958 - 1987; F-144-1; 8 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the administration and operation of the WDCAG. Includes minutes, reports, correspondence, and other documents.
  - Executive meetings, 1958 - 1982; F-144-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Notices, 1965 - 1975; F-144-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
    Textual records; Graphic materials
  - Financial reports, 1965 - 1979; F-144-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Membership, 1966 - 1982; F-144-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Constitution, 1971 - 1983; F-144-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - President's executive file, 1983 - 1987; F-144-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Membership lists, 1971-1984; F-144-1-0-0-8 (144-5)
  - Executive correspondence, reports, conference proceedings, 1984-2010; F-144-1-0-0-9 (144-5)
  - Executive correspondence, reports, conference proceedings, 1994-1997; F-144-1-0-0-10 (144-5)
- Correspondence, 1963 - 2011; F-144-2; 12 cm of textual records (144-8)
  Series consists of letters written or received by the officers of the WDCAG on behalf of the organization.
  - Correspondence, 1963 - 1968; F-144-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Correspondence, 1969; F-144-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Correspondence, 1970; F-144-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 144-1)
  - Correspondence, 1971 - 1972; F-144-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Correspondence, 1973; F-144-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Correspondence, 1974 - 1975; F-144-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Correspondence, 1976 - 1979; F-144-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Correspondence, 1980 - 1985; F-144-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
- Annual meetings, 1958 - 2006; F-144-3; 16 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the annual meetings of the UDCAG. Includes minutes, programs, abstracts, presented papers and other documents.
  - Annual meetings, 1958 - 1970; F-144-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Annual meetings, 1971 - 1973; F-144-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Annual meetings, 1974 - 1979; F-144-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 144-2)
  - Annual meetings, 1980 - 1985; F-144-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
  - Annual meetings, 1987 - 1988; F-144-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
    Textual records; Graphic materials; Cartographic materials
  - Annual meetings 1/2, 1975 - 1992; F-144-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
    Textual records; Photographic materials; Cartographic materials
  - Annual meetings 2/2, 1975 - 1992; F-144-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
  - Annual meetings, 1998; F-144-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
  - Annual meetings, 2005 - 2006; F-144-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
  - Annual meetings, 1994-1997; F-144-3-0-0-10 (144-6)
  - Annual meetings, 1998-2011; F-144-3-0-0-11 (144-6)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1987; F-144-3-0-0-12 (144-6)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1987; F-144-3-0-0-13 (144-6)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1987; F-144-3-0-0-14 (144-6)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1987; F-144-3-0-0-15 (144-6)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1986-1987; F-144-3-0-0-16 (144-7)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1986-1987; F-144-3-0-0-17 (144-7)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 1986-1987; F-144-3-0-0-18 (144-7)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 2001-2002; F-144-3-0-0-19 (144-8)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 2002; F-144-3-0-0-20 (144-8)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 2000; F-144-3-0-0-21 (144-8)
  - Annual meeting planning (held at SFU), 2002; F-144-3-0-0-22 (144-8)
- Publications, 1960 - 2006; F-144-4; 15 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the official newsletter of the Division as well as publications dealing with geographical research in western Canada.
  - Newsletter, Western Division, 1970 - 1980; F-144-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 144-3)
  - Newsletter, Western Division, 1980 - 1989; F-144-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - B. C. Geographical Newsletter, 1974; F-144-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - The Geography Newsletter, 1974 - 1975; F-144-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - The Canadian Association of Geographers, British Columbia Division, Occasional Papers, 1960; F-144-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - The Canadian Association of Geographers, British Columbia Division, Occasional Papers, 1961; F-144-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - The Canadian Association of Geographers, British Columbia Division, Occasional Papers, 1962; F-144-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - The Canadian Association of Geographers, British Columbia Division, Occasional Papers, 1963; F-144-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - Newsletter, Western Division, 1990 - 1994; F-144-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-144-4-0-0-2.1.
  - Newsletter, Western Division, 2006; F-144-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 144-4)
  - Newsletter, western division, 1975-1989; F-144-4-0-0-11 (144-7)
  - Newsletter, western division, 1990-1994; F-144-4-0-0-12 (144-7)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1990; F-144-4-0-0-13 (144-7)
  - Newsletters, 1990-1999; F-144-4-0-0-14 (144-7)